<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-03-06T14:03:19+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">jackx</title><subtitle>A collection of thoughts and ideas</subtitle><author><name>Jack</name></author><entry><title type="html">Tourist Visa options for Vietnam</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-my-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tourist Visa options for Vietnam" /><published>2025-03-05T00:00:00+07:00</published><updated>2025-03-05T00:00:00+07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-my-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-my-blog/"><![CDATA[<p>Planning a trip to Vietnam? Understanding the country’s visa policies is essential. This guide provides up-to-date information on the 45-day visa exemption and the 90-day e-visa options available for tourists.</p>

<p><img src="/assets/images/visa.webp" alt="Alt text" /></p>

<h2 id="45-day-visa-exemption">45-Day Visa Exemption</h2>

<p>As of August 15, 2023, Vietnam has extended its visa exemption policy, allowing citizens from 13 countries to stay visa-free for up to 45 days. The eligible countries are:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Germany</strong></li>
  <li><strong>France</strong></li>
  <li><strong>Italy</strong></li>
  <li><strong>Spain</strong></li>
  <li><strong>United Kingdom</strong></li>
  <li><strong>Russia</strong></li>
  <li><strong>Japan</strong></li>
  <li><strong>South Korea</strong></li>
  <li><strong>Denmark</strong></li>
  <li><strong>Sweden</strong></li>
  <li><strong>Norway</strong></li>
  <li><strong>Finland</strong></li>
  <li><strong>Belarus</strong></li>
</ul>

<p>Citizens from these nations can enter Vietnam without a visa and remain for up to 45 days, regardless of passport type or entry purpose. Ensure your passport is valid for at least six months from your date of entry and has at least two blank pages.</p>

<h2 id="90-day-e-visa">90-Day E-Visa</h2>

<p>Vietnam offers a convenient e-visa system for citizens of all countries and territories. Key features of the 90-day e-visa include:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Validity</strong>: Up to 90 days, with options for single or multiple entries.</li>
  <li><strong>Application</strong>: Apply online through the official Vietnam Immigration Department’s e-visa portal.</li>
  <li><strong>Fees</strong>: $25 USD for single-entry and $50 USD for multiple-entry, payable electronically. Note that fees are non-refundable, even if the application is denied.</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Application Process</strong>:</p>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Prepare Required Documents</strong>:
    <ul>
      <li>A valid passport with at least six months’ validity remaining.</li>
      <li>A recent digital passport-sized photo.</li>
      <li>A scanned copy of your passport’s biographical page.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong>Submit Application</strong>:
    <ul>
      <li>Visit the official e-visa portal <a href="https://evisa.xuatnhapcanh.gov.vn/">Vietnam e‑visa portal</a>.</li>
      <li>Complete the online application form with accurate personal and travel information.</li>
      <li>Upload the required documents.</li>
      <li>Pay the visa fee using the available electronic payment methods.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong>Receive and Print E-Visa</strong>:
    <ul>
      <li>Processing typically takes 3-5 working days.</li>
      <li>Once approved, download and print your e-visa approval letter.</li>
      <li>Present the printed e-visa along with your passport upon arrival in Vietnam.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ol>

<p><strong>Important Notes</strong>:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Ensure all information provided in the application matches your passport details.</li>
  <li>The e-visa is valid for entry through designated international checkpoints, including airports, land borders, and seaports. Verify that your intended point of entry accepts e-visas.</li>
  <li>Overstaying your visa can result in fines or deportation. Plan your travel accordingly to avoid any issues.</li>
</ul>

<p>For the most current information and to apply for your e-visa, visit the official Vietnam Immigration Department’s e-visa portal <a href="https://evisa.xuatnhapcanh.gov.vn/">Vietnam e‑visa portal</a>.</p>

<p>By understanding these visa options, you can better plan your visit to Vietnam and enjoy all the rich experiences this vibrant country has to offer.</p>

<hr />

<p><em>Note: Visa policies are subject to change. It’s advisable to check the latest information from official sources before planning your trip.</em></p>]]></content><author><name>Jack</name></author><category term="general" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Planning a trip to Vietnam? Understanding the country’s visa policies is essential. This guide provides up-to-date information on the 45-day visa exemption and the 90-day e-visa options available for tourists.]]></summary></entry></feed>